Tell me.
告訴我
-Tell me! -Dr. Tokai…
-快告訴我！ -渡海醫生
Tell me!
告訴我！
Iinuma…
飯沼…
Tatsuji Iinuma…
飯沼達次
Dr. Saeki!
佐伯醫生！
Dr. Tokai!
渡海醫生！
It's Dr. Saeki!
佐伯醫生他…
It finally happened?
終於發生了嗎？
The professor… collapsed?
教授昏倒了？
What's his condition? Understood, I'm on my way!
情況如何？知道了，我馬上回去
One, two, three!
一、二、三
Dr. Saeki!
佐伯醫生！
-Take him to the operating room! -Right!
-立刻送到手術室 -是！
Hold that.
-抱歉我來遲了 -再往後一點
-Prepare for radiography! -Bring his chart.
-準備造影 -導管拿來
-Prepare a cardiac catheter! -Right.
-準備心臟插管 -是
-Let me help. -We don't need your help.
-我也來幫忙 -不需要你的幫忙
Go back to Teika where you belong!
跟帝華大學的人一起滾回去吧
-Get the aortic balloon pump! -Okay!
-把動脈氣球幫浦拿來 -是！
-Move now. -Go!
-快點 -快啊！
Right!
是！
Dr. Tokai?
渡海醫生？
Emergency procedures on Dr. Saeki have been completed
經過緊急處置，佐伯教授目前
and he's currently stable.
情況穩定下來了
As for his exam results,
他的檢查結果顯示
a narrowing was found in the left coronary artery.
左冠狀動脈有變窄的情形
We believe the cause is
我們認為原因是
anomalous left coronary artery from the pulmonary artery.
從肺動脈引起的左冠狀動脈異常
Normally, the left coronary artery should emerge from the aorta,
一般來說 左冠狀動脈應該從大動脈出來
but in rare cases, it originates from the pulmonary artery.
但也有罕見的病例是從肺動脈流出
As a result, the heart doesn't receive sufficient oxygen.
這會導致心臟無法接收到充足的氧氣
A serious condition leading to impaired heart function.
造成心臟功能惡化的嚴重病症
Additionally, he's suffering from mitral valve regurgitation.
再加上二尖瓣閉鎖不全的併發症
He could suffer a fatal heart attack at any time.
隨時可能會因心肌梗塞致命
-We must operate at once. -I can't believe this.
-必須立刻動手術 -真不敢相信
Dr. Saeki's own mitral valve…
佐伯醫生的二尖瓣…
The only one at Tojo who can operate is…
東城大學能做這種手術的只有…
-Where's Dr. Tokai? -He's nowhere to be found.
-渡海醫生呢？ -到處都找不到他
Oh! I saw him earlier!
我剛才有看到他
During Dr. Saeki's procedure, he took off somewhere.
佐伯醫生接受手術時 我看到他去了別的地方
-What? -Dr. Sera, go track him down.
-什麼？ -世良，把他找出來
Right.
好
I saw him, but I have no idea where he was heading.
我也有看到他，但不曉得他去哪裡了
-Where could he have gone? -I'm sorry.
-他可能會去哪裡？ -抱歉
Say it!
快說！
Tell me!
告訴我！
Tatsuji Iinuma…
飯沼達次
-Tatsuji Iinuma. -What?
-飯沼達次 -什麼？
The name Tatsuji Iinuma was searched.
你搜尋了飯沼達次這個名字
Could that be…
該不會…
Yes, it does appear that Tatsuji Iinuma is admitted here.
飯沼達次先生確實在這家醫院
Which room?
哪一間病房？
-I would like to hear your reason-- -Which room?
-你先告訴我原因 -哪一間病房？
-He's on a restricted floor.
-外部人員禁止進入的樓層 -病房號碼是？
Room 421.
421號房
Ms. Kinoshita.
木下小姐
Dr. Tokai was here, wasn't he?
渡海先生果然來這裡了，是吧？
He's searching for Tatsuji Iinuma.
他在找飯沼達次先生吧？
What is he planning to do? Which way did he go?
他到底打算做什麼？他去哪裡了？
Thank you.
謝謝你
Someone, call the guards!
快叫保全！
-Please stop. -You don't have permission to be here.
-站住 -你沒有資格來這裡
Dr. Tokai, what are you doing at a time like this?
渡海醫生，都這種時候了 你在做什麼？
-Dr. Saeki is seriously ill! -You save him then.
-佐伯教授病倒了！ -那你去救他啊
-Someone stop him! -Someone, please!
-誰來阻止他啊！ -快來人啊！
-Just wait a second. -Move it!
-你先等一下 -礙事！
No one is here.
這裡沒人啊
Dr. Saeki?
佐伯醫生？
Yes?
啊？
-What about Mr. Iinuma? -I released him as you ordered.
-飯沼先生呢？ -我照你的吩咐，讓他出院了
Dr. Saeki!
佐伯醫生！
Release…
讓飯沼先生…
Mr. Iinuma…
出院
I see.
這樣啊
I can't believe it.
真不敢相信
Collapsing in my own hospital.
我在自己工作的醫院病倒了
Please.
拜託您
You have to focus on your own health now.
一定要專注在自己的健康上
The election is around the corner…
理事長選舉就快到了
They've done it now.
他們還真厲害
Wait, Dr. Tokai…
等等，渡海醫生
-Mr. Kobayashi. -So it was you?
-小林先生 -果然是你
Could you please leave?
可以請你離開嗎？
-Where did you send him? -Who knows.
-你把他送去哪裡了？ -不知道
I simply released him, on Dr. Saeki's orders.
我只是遵照佐伯醫生的指示 讓他出院而已
Where he was transferred, I do not know.
我不知道他被轉去哪裡了
You'll have to ask Dr. Saeki yourself.
你得自己去問佐伯醫生
Pardon me. Sorry.
不好意思，抱歉
-What is this about? -How's the professor?
-那是怎麼回事？ -教授怎麼樣了？
The emergency procedures were finished, but he's still in danger.
做了緊急處置，但他還是有生命危險
He's fine. I'll save him.
他不會有事，我會救他
And then I'll kill him myself.
然後我會親手殺了他
I never thought I would have a mitral valve problem myself.
沒想到我自己會得二尖瓣閉鎖不全症
I would prefer to operate on myself, but I suppose that's not possible.
我很想自己主刀 但我想這應該行不通
How would you like us to proceed?
您想怎麼處理呢？
-Dr. Tokai… -Where were you?
-渡海醫生 -你去哪裡了？
I'll operate.
我會主刀
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼鬼話？
So…
不然呢？
Who else do you think could do it?
除了我，有誰可以？
Okay, I'll be leaving then.
好，那我先走了
I refuse.
我拒絕
But… who else can do it?
但是有誰可以主刀？
I hate to say it, but Dr. Tokai is the only one with the right skills.
我很不想承認 但只有渡海先生有這種能力
The Caesar.
用凱撒啊
Use the Caesar for your operation?
用凱撒替您動手術？
This will be a difficult procedure requiring precise work.
這場最高難度的手術需要精密的技術
I believe Caesar is the best option.
我認為凱撒是最好的選擇
These are…
這是…
my orders.
我的命令
Yes, sir!
是！
We will definitely make the surgery a success!
我們一定會確保手術順利完成
The master of the scalpel's own surgery
外科手術權威自己的手術
and he chooses to have it done with the Caesar?
居然選擇用凱撒來做？
The board has caught wind of Dr. Saeki's condition.
理事們聽說佐伯生病的事情了
I wasn't sure what would happen,
我不確定情況會怎樣
but this surely confirms my victory in the board chairman election.
但這樣一來，理事長選舉我贏定了
Dr. Saeki fell after covering up your mistake, Dr. Nishizaki.
佐伯教授為了掩蓋西崎教授的失誤
He was under too much pressure.
勉強動手術才會昏倒的
I've made no mistakes.
我才沒有失誤
Dr. Saeki just happened to barge in during my procedure.
只是在我處理到一半時 佐伯闖進來而已
You reap what you sow.
這是他自作自受
-Dr. Nishizaki! -The age of the scalpel comes to an end.
-西崎教授 -醫生親手執刀的時代就此結束了
Take care of yourself.
你自己保重
So the professor has put his fate in the hands of technology.
看來教授將自己的命運交給科技
A declaration of defeat, you could say.
這可說是佐伯外科的敗北宣言了
Losing to a robot like this?
輸給了那樣的機器人？
NO DATA
（無數據）
All the data is gone!
數據全都沒了
You're still here, Dr. Takashina?
你還在這裡啊，高階醫生？
There's nothing for you here.
這裡不需要你了
Are you still trying to stand in our way?
你還打算在這裡擋路嗎？
Is everyone here?
大家都在嗎？
About Dr. Saeki's Caesar operation,
關於佐伯醫生的凱撒手術
I will lead the surgery.
將由我主刀
Dr. Sekikawa and Dr. Kakitani will assist.
助手是關川和垣谷
Okay.
-是
I would also like to call on anyone able to lend a hand.
我希望能夠幫忙的人也一起參與
Understood?
知道嗎？
Dr. Saeki's life represents the life of all patients in this hospital.
佐伯醫生的命 就等於是醫院所有患者的命
We must work together and save Dr. Saeki's life!
我們得同心協力守護佐伯醫生的性命
-Right. -Yes.
-是
Dr. Sera. A word, please.
世良，借步說話
Yes?
什麼事？
We've received a complaint from Sakura Hospital about Dr. Tokai.
我們收到櫻花醫院對渡海提出的抗議
At a time like this…
在這麼重要的時刻…
Keep an eye on him, will you?
你去盯好渡海，好嗎？
-What? -There's no telling what he might do.
-什麼？ -他的行為難以預料
I have no intention of dealing with him during this operation.
我希望這次手術別跟他扯上關係
Got it?
懂嗎？
Yes.
是
Leading up to Dr. Saeki's operation,
佐伯教授的手術之前
preparations began to improve the skills of the entire team.
佐伯外科的所有人員 都開始訓練自己的能力
The operation at hand
教授這次的手術
will be full of difficulty.
會非常困難
Dr. Saeki requires a bypass operation using the mammary artery
這次手術需要用內乳動脈 對左冠狀動脈做搭橋術
for the left coronary artery, and mitral valve repair.
以及二尖瓣修補手術
Two entirely different operations,
這是兩種截然不同的手術
requiring an approach from two separate locations.
所以需要從兩個地方進入
But the doctor's cardiopulmonary function was weak
但是教授的心肺功能低下
and the time available after anesthesia is just two hours.
而能夠麻醉的時間只有兩小時
Completing two operations in two hours was thought to be impossible.
在兩小時內要完成這兩個手術 幾乎是不可能
A Caesar operation like this has never been done.
用凱撒同時做兩個手術是史無前例的
And in only two hours…
還只能在短短兩小時內…
-Shouldn't we ask Dr. Takashina? -This is Tojo's operation.
-要不要問高階醫生？ -這是東城大學的手術
We don't have room for traitors.
這裡沒有叛徒的位置
The only thing to do is rehearse the operation and analyze the results.
我們只需要模擬手術過程並檢討結果
Yes, sir.
是
You should be on that team, Dr. Takashina.
高階先生你應該參與的
I've already betrayed Tojo twice.
我已經背叛東城大學兩次
That may be true,
或許是吧
but you've never betrayed a patient.
但高階醫生你從來不會背叛患者
And on top of that,
更何況
you know more about the Caesar than anyone at Tojo.
你比東城大學的人都了解凱撒
This simulator can be used, right?
那個模擬器是可以用的吧？
The Teika team took all the data from it, leaving nothing behind.
帝華大學把數據全都拿走了 裡面一點都不剩
Like a game console without a game.
就像是沒有遙控器的遊戲機一樣
So, it can't help us after all.
所以完全幫不上忙了
Dr. Sera, aren't you supposed to be watching Dr. Tokai?
世良，你不是應該盯著渡海醫生嗎？
-Yes, that's right. -He just left.
-是啊 -他剛剛出去了
What?
什麼？
-Where? -There.
-他去哪裡？ -那裡
Crap, that's not good. Now what do I do?
可惡，這下不妙，我該怎麼辦？
The Caesar.
用凱撒動手術
You know it won't work.
你知道是行不通的
It won't be just the election you lose,
你可能不只會失去選舉
but your life as well.
還可能失去性命
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
I want you to operate after all.
還是由你來主刀吧
Did you think I'd come begging to you?
你以為我會這樣求你嗎？
But the fact is that you know it's the only way.
但事實上，你知道這是唯一的方法
You don't care about saving my life.
你不是真的想救我的命
You just want to know about the patient I'm protecting.
你只是想知道我保護的病人在哪裡
Don't underestimate me, Dr. Tokai.
別小看我，渡海醫生
Sometimes, there are things more important than life itself.
有時候，人有比生命更重要的東西
Even if I die,
我佐伯清剛
I would never bow to a man like you.
就算死了也不會向你低頭
My surgery will be done by the Caesar.
我的手術要用凱撒來進行
For my survival,
除了凱撒
that is the only way.
沒有其他方法救得了我
Well then, if that's so you can rest at ease
那好吧，你就在這裡
and die.
靜靜等死
-Dr. Takashina… -I have something to ask of you.
-高階 -我有事想問您幫忙
Data?
數據？
Yes.
對
The data saved inside the Caesar Simulator from the trials at Tojo.
在東城大學進行試驗時 模擬器儲存的數據
Would you lend it to me?
能不能借我參考？
I won't.
不行
That data is three long years of hard labor.
那可是我們帝華大學 花了長達三年累積的數據
I value it like my own life.
跟我的命一樣寶貴
You can't just come asking for that.
不能這樣借給你
Isn't it part of our collaborative research?
但那不是合作研究的一部分嗎？
Our research was concluded with the last trial.
研究在上次臨床手術就結束了
You're wrong.
不是的
I haven't completed my paper just yet.
我的論文還沒寫完
If this is about the paper, I already have one.
這篇論文已經有人寫出來了
I had Dr. Sakaguchi write it.
我請坂口寫了
In fact,
事實上
I was just on my way to submit it
我正要交給
to Mr. Ikenaga from the Japan Surgical Journal.
《日本外科期刊》的池永主編
In that case…
那樣的話
What was I working for all this time?
我一直以來的努力都是為了什麼？
What was it for?
為了什麼？
It was for me.
都是為了我
Well…
這個嘛…
you'll just have to
你還得
work a little harder.
再多加點油吧
Takashina.
高階
Dr. Nishizaki.
西崎教授
What does the Caesar mean to you?
對您來說，凱撒是什麼？
What is research to you?
研究又是什麼？
Wasn't it made to save people's lives?
難道不是為了拯救人命的嗎？
Thanks for all your work.
一直以來辛苦你了
-Dr. Nishizaki! -Hey! Stop!
-西崎教授！ -站住
You!
你！
You call yourself a doctor?
你好意思自稱為醫生嗎？
Yes.
是啊
I am a doctor.
我是醫生沒錯
Tojo's doctor will be leaving now.
這位東城大學的醫生要離開了
Make sure he's sent off properly.
好好送客
Excuse me.
不好意思
I wasn't trying to butt in.
我不是想妨礙你們工作
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
I…
我…
I would like to ask you to operate.
想請你主刀
To save Dr. Saeki's life,
為了救佐伯教授
we need your help.
我們需要你的幫忙
The data from this operation will be crucial for our case study.
這次手術的數據會是珍貴的病例
It will also be a fine souvenir for Teika University.
對帝華大學來說 也會是個不錯的紀念品
The chairman election win will go to your team at Teika.
理事長選舉也會是帝華大學的勝利
It pains me, but it's what we must do.
雖然很難受，但也只能這樣了
To save Dr. Saeki's life,
只要能救佐伯教授
if we can keep him alive,
只要他能活下來
then so be it.
我們什麼都願意
We must save his life. Nothing more.
我們只是想救他一命，僅此而已
Wasn't it made to save people's lives?
難道不是為了拯救人命的嗎？
Please.
拜託
Please help us.
請幫幫我們
Thanks for all your work.
一直以來辛苦你了
Dr. Nishizaki has thrown me under the bus.
西崎教授拋棄了我
I've dedicated everything to writing my paper.
我為論文奉獻了一切
But now, Dr. Nishizaki doesn't need me anymore.
但現在，西崎教授不再需要我了
He had someone else write it.
他改叫別人寫論文了
For years now,
這麼多年來
I poured my heart and soul into working for that man.
我為那個人全心全意地付出
And as a result…
結果…
this is what I get.
卻落得這種下場
I have dedicated years of work to Dr. Saeki,
我也為佐伯教授奉獻了多年的心血
supporting him.
支持著他
So I understand your feelings
所以我懂你的感受
and your deep regret.
和你的悔恨
Let us support him together.
我們一起支持佐伯教授吧
Please!
拜託！
Dr. Kurosaki.
黑崎醫生
I would be…
我…
honored to help you.
很榮幸能幫得上忙
With Dr. Takashina back on the team,
高階醫生加入醫療團隊後
preparations for Dr. Saeki's Caesar surgery continued onward.
東城大學繼續準備著 佐伯教授的凱撒手術
We only have one week until the operation.
離手術只剩一週
I would like you to dig up
我想請各位查查看
any previous files of similar Darwin operations.
先前有沒有類似的達爾文案例
We'll need to think globally.
要以世界規模來找
I'll ask acquaintances from my time studying in New York and Paris.
我去問問在紐約和巴黎留學時的熟人
I can speak Italian and German. I'll see what I can find there.
我會義大利語和德語 我往這個方向找
These guys…
這些傢伙
Right then. Everyone, let's find simulation cases.
那好，請大家去找模擬手術的病例
-Right!
-是！
Listen up! Let's show the world what Tojo University is made of!
大家聽好了 向全世界展現東城大學的精神吧！
-Yes! -All right!
-是！
So Dr. Takashina is on the team now?
高階醫生加入手術團隊了？
Yes.
是
They're ready to "show the world what Tojo is made of."
他們準備好要向全世界 展現東城大學的精神了
Is that so?
這樣啊
-Just one thing. -Yes?
-有件事想拜託你 -什麼事？
I want to see them in action.
我想看他們準備的樣子
Could someone film it for me?
可以拍給我看嗎？
Certainly.
當然可以
All right.
好
We don't need that. Get it out of here.
不需要那個，拿走吧
Please let us borrow your wisdom.
我想請教您的高見
Make sure this constricted part doesn't come off…
確保這個狹窄的部分不會掉下來…
Right there.
就是那裡
Where do we approach the coronary artery?
我們要從哪裡進去處理冠狀動脈？
That's the question…
是啊…
We still haven't found a similar case.
目前還沒找到類似案例
We'll have to conduct simulations and create a plan that way.
我們只能進行模擬手術然後擬定計畫
Like walking through an uncharted desert.
這就像不看地圖穿越沙漠一樣
We must keep walking forward
我們必須勇往直前
believing we'll make it through.
並相信我們會成功
Without a prior example,
因為沒有先例
simulations had to be done for each variation of the arm insertion.
機械手臂每插入一個位置 都需要做模擬練習
We're out of time.
沒有時間了
This approach will make the bypass take too long.
如果從這邊進入 搭橋時間會變得太久
-Let's try again. -Right.
-再試一次吧 -好
Only a week remained until operation day.
離手術只剩一週了
Still without results to show after hours of trial and error,
經過不斷地嘗試和失敗後 還是沒有實質的成果
Dr. Takashina and the others were becoming anxious.
高階醫生等人都變得越來越焦慮
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
We need your help to save Dr. Saeki.
我們需要你幫忙救佐伯教授
Might as well just let me do it myself.
乾脆讓我主刀不就好了
The doctor asked specifically for the Caesar…
教授特別說要用凱撒…
Dr. Tokai is the only person we can rely on.
果然還是只能依賴渡海醫生了
But he and Dr. Saeki continue to grow further apart.
但他和佐伯教授之間的鴻溝越來越大
If we can find the root cause of that,
如果能找出他們不和的原因
Dr. Tokai may agree to help with the operation.
渡海醫生或許會答應參與手術
The root cause?
原因？
I think it has something to do with that person named Tatsuji Iinuma.
我覺得一定跟飯沼達次這個人有關係
The person Dr. Tokai is searching for.
就是渡海先生在找的人
That picture you found with the forceps
你之前找到有止血鉗的X光片
might have something to do with it as well.
或許跟他們有關係
But if you get in Dr. Tokai's way,
如果你擋到渡海醫生的路
you'll be crushed.
你會被毀掉的
I don't think we should meddle in this too much.
可是我覺得還是別再追查下去比較好
It's to save the doctor.
這是為了救教授
I'm going to search Dr. Tokai's room again.
我再去渡海醫生的房間找找看
Dr. Tokai?
渡海醫生？
Yes. I'm hoping to ask him to operate the Caesar.
對，我想請他擔任凱撒手術的主刀
What will the professor say?
教授會怎麼說？
It's to save his life.
這是為了救他的命
You're right.
你說得對
I'll talk to Dr. Tokai myself.
我會找渡海談談
I knew his father a bit, in fact.
其實我也認識他父親
I've wanted to talk to him about this for a while.
我一直想要找他好好談一談
Nothing. It's not here.
沒有，不在這裡
Maybe we should forget about it.
或許我們該忘了這件事
Dr. Tokai will be back soon anyway.
渡海醫生也快回來了
He just sits around here eating rice.
他就只會坐在這裡吃飯
Rice?
米飯？
Could it be…
該不會…
I found it.
找到了
This is the photo I saw.
我看到的就是這個
There really is a pair of forceps.
真的有止血鉗
The patient's name is Tatsuji Iinuma.
病患的名字是飯沼達次
Physician's name, Ichiro Tokai.
主治醫生是渡海一郎
Hey, Dr. Tokai.
渡海
I would like to speak to you.
我有事想跟你談談
It's about Dr. Saeki's Caesar operation.
關於佐伯教授的凱撒手術…
Convince the doctor to use a scalpel.
你去說服教授改成一般手術吧
If we don't, he'll die.
不然他可就死定了
Dr. Tokai…
渡海醫生
Wait, Dr. Tokai.
等一下，渡海
Get a grip!
你鬧夠了吧？
Dr. Tokai…
渡海醫生
Wait, Dr. Tokai.
等一下，渡海
Get a grip!
你鬧夠了吧？
That photograph…
這張X光片…
Why do you have this?
你怎麼會有這個？
Where did you get this?
你去哪裡拿到的？
Um…
那個…
Give it back.
還給我
It's mine.
這是我的
What are you doing, Dr. Tokai?
渡海，你在做什麼？
Why do you have that?
你為什麼有那個？
A grudge, is it?
懷恨在心，是嗎？
You're the son of Tojo's biggest embarrassment.
你父親是東城大學最大的恥辱
Get out, Dr. Tokai.
渡海，滾出去
I thought I would ask for your help, but I was wrong. We don't need you.
我本來想請你幫忙的 但我錯了，我們不需要你了
You'll never set foot in the operating room again.
也不准你再進去手術室
You'll wait at home until the operation is complete, understood?
你就待在家裡 等到教授的手術結束，懂嗎？
What?
什麼？
This is my home.
這裡就是我家啊
Get out!
滾出去！
Dr. Kurosaki.
黑崎醫生
Did you know about that photograph?
你知道那張X光片的事情嗎？
It's none of your business.
不關你們的事
Dr. Tokai is searching for Tatsuji Iinuma.
渡海醫生在找飯沼達次
That's why he went to Teika University
所以他之前才會去帝華大學
and why he went to Sakura Hospital when Dr. Saeki fell ill.
教授倒下時，他跑去櫻花醫院 也是因為這件事
He's looking for Iinuma? What is this about?
他在找飯沼達次？這是怎麼回事？
That's supposed to be left in the past.
過去的事情就該讓它過去啊
What happened?
發生了什麼事嗎？
When I first joined this hospital, that man was my mentor.
我剛到這家醫院時，指導教授就是
Dr. Tokai's father.
渡海的父親
The doctor is mistaken.
教授弄錯了
Ichiro Tokai was an outstanding doctor.
渡海一郎是一位優秀的醫生
But he was ambitious, always aiming for the top.
但他野心勃勃，只想著要往上爬
He had difficulty getting along with the other doctors.
和當時的教授關係很不好
He was put in charge of operating on a patient named Tatsuji Iinuma.
當時，他替一位名叫飯沼的患者開刀
A simple cardiovascular surgery.
那只是一場簡單的心臟手術
Dr. Tokai, about Mr. Iinuma's post-operation care…
渡海醫生，飯沼先生的術後護理…
I happened to catch a glimpse of the X-ray that he was holding.
我碰巧看見他手上拿了 飯沼先生的X光片
-That's… -None of your business.
-那是… -不關你的事
In the patient's chest
患者的胸部
was a pair of forceps.
插了一把止血鉗
He left them inside the patient.
他留在病患體內忘記取出
Clearly medical malpractice.
這顯然是醫療過失
How will you take responsibility for this?
你要怎麼負責？
After his incriminating mistake,
犯下這個大錯的渡海一郎
Dr. Tokai was expelled from Tojo.
被東城大學開除了
I've heard that the forceps were removed in a secret procedure
聽說院方做了秘密手術 將止血鉗取出了
and the story never gained traction.
這件事就沒有鬧大
Only a handful of our staff know
現在只有少數人知道
about Tojo's tainted past.
東城大學過去的這個汙點
After that, Dr. Saeki felt pity for Ichiro Tokai's son
在那之後，佐伯教授 因為同情渡海一郎的兒子
and invited him into his practice.
所以把他招來自己的團隊
That's Dr. Tokai.
就是渡海醫生
That explains why he feels the need to follow Dr. Saeki's orders.
難怪他對佐伯醫生的指示百般服從
I'm sure he resents it on the inside.
我敢說他應該恨在心裡
After his revered father was expelled,
優秀的父親被趕出去之後
someone had to take his place.
取代他位置的那個人
That was Dr. Saeki.
就是佐伯教授
Dr. Tokai can't be trusted.
不能信任渡海
We'll operate on Dr. Saeki without him.
我們只能靠自己為佐伯醫生動手術
Dr. Sera.
世良
You'll be joining the operating team.
你也加入手術團隊
We don't need Dr. Tokai's scalpel.
我們不需要渡海執刀
You'll be crushed.
你會被毀掉的
Nekota…
貓田小姐
What were you talking to Dr. Kurosaki about?
黑崎醫生跟你說了什麼？
Does it have something to do
跟渡海先生被趕出去
with Dr. Tokai being kicked out?
有什麼關係嗎？
-Well… -Was it about Ichiro Tokai?
-那個… -是渡海一郎的事嗎？
Do you know about him?
你知道他的事嗎？
You.
你啊
What did you hear?
聽說了些什麼？
Nekota.
貓田護理師
What are you doing here?
你在這裡做什麼？
Get back to work.
快回去工作
Understood.
我知道了
She's being obedient today.
她今天很聽話嘛
So?
所以呢？
What did you hear from Dr. Kurosaki?
你從黑崎醫生那裡聽說了什麼？
TOJO UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL INTERN DORMITORY
（東城大學附屬醫院 實習醫生宿舍）
-I missed dinner. -You scared me.
-我錯過晚餐了 -嚇到我了
-Got a rice cooker? -Dr. Tokai. Yes, I do, but…
-你有炊飯器吧？ -渡海醫生，有是有，但是…
I see…
這樣啊
You heard the whole story.
他說了那麼多啊
But going forward,
但是之後
you must focus on your duties as a nurse.
你專心做好護理師的工作就好
You need to keep it a secret.
這件事應該要保密
That goes for Nekota and your close friend Dr. Sera too.
貓田就不用說了 也不能告訴跟你很要好的世良醫生
If I were to tell Dr. Saeki,
要是我告訴佐伯醫生
I could have anyone fired in an instant.
立刻就能把人開除掉
Do you understand?
聽懂了嗎？
Yes, ma'am.
我知道了
Um, everyone here is asleep so try to keep it down.
大家都睡了，請小聲一點
-I know that. -Okay. Thanks.
-知道啦 -好，拜託了
-Hold it. -What is it?
-等一下 -什麼事？
These are in my way.
這些很礙事
Sorry.
抱歉
I was practicing and…
我在練習
Average guys like me need to practice at home to keep up.
像我這樣的普通人 需要多練習才能趕得上別人
I bet you do.
說得沒錯
I have to keep up with my studies.
所以我必須多念書
I've been put on the Caesar team and asked to conduct simulations.
他們讓我加入凱撒團隊進行模擬試驗
I don't know if I'll be able to help.
不知道我幫不幫得上忙
There has never been a case like this.
以前從沒有過這種手術
I still can't grasp exactly what the Caesar can do and how.
我還是不確定凱撒到底能做到什麼 也不知道能怎麼辦到
The doctors are having a hard time as well.
前輩們也遇到許多困難
Out of time again.
又沒有時間了
I hope we can find a way.
要是能有所突破就好了
Go find it yourself. Go ask.
自己去找啊，去問問看啊
Ask? But where?
去哪裡問？
If you're looking for cases or papers,
如果要找病例或論文
go to the best source we've got.
就去有最多資源的地方
About the Caesar paper submitted recently,
關於最近交給我的凱撒論文
we've gotten confirmation on its publication
我們確認將於下一期
in the next issue of the Journal.
《日本外科期刊》中刊登
Thank you.
太謝謝您了
It will be out just before the election.
理事長選舉在即
Just in time.
正好能趕上呢
this is all thanks to you, Mr. Ikenaga.
這完全都是池永主編的功勞
This time, I'll finally exceed Dr. Saeki's Impact Factor.
這一次，我的影響因子 終於能超越佐伯教授了
I will win the chairman election.
我會贏得理事長選舉的
Well. As for Dr. Saeki himself,
至於佐伯教授那邊
he's not exactly in a position to compete anyway.
他應該也沒有餘力跟我角逐
I hear his operation will be quite difficult.
我聽說他的手術非常困難
That's right.
沒錯
We were once great rivals,
我們曾是競爭對手
but I do pray for his swift recovery.
但我確實希望他平安無事
I'll pay you back after the election.
選舉之後我會再向您道謝
Until then.
再見
Victory
我
is mine.
贏定了
You call yourself a doctor?
你好意思自稱為醫生嗎？
Yes. I am a doctor.
是啊，我是醫生沒錯
Come in.
請進
-Excuse me. -Pardon me.
-打擾了 -不好意思
Sorry for the short notice.
抱歉突然來訪
Dr. Sera would like to speak to you about the Caesar operation.
世良醫生想跟您聊聊凱撒手術的事
Yes.
是的
I see.
這樣啊
You don't plan on asking me to show you Dr. Nishizaki's Caesar research, do you?
你該不會要我 讓你看西崎醫生的凱撒論文吧？
The paper would indeed
這份論文確實
give you a good hint about Dr. Saeki's operation,
能夠為佐伯醫生的手術帶來一些提示
but I cannot provide that information.
但我不能給你看
A paper is a doctor's life.
因為論文就是醫生的命啊
I know.
我知道
There's no way he'll show you the paper before it's published.
他不可能會給你看還未刊登的論文
-So what should we do? -Are you stupid?
-那該怎麼辦才好？ -你是笨蛋吧？
Maybe.
是
Well, in that case,
那就照笨蛋的方法
maybe you should just ask him anyway.
直接問他就好了
"So what should we do?"
“那該怎麼辦才好？”
So what should we do?
那該怎麼辦才好？
What?
什麼？
Um,
那個…
these are Dr. Saeki's clinical records.
這是佐伯教授的病歷
Would you be willing to share any advice?
能夠請您給一些建議嗎？
There's no way he'll give us any advice.
他不可能會告訴我的
You're right.
你說得沒錯
Well then,
那樣的話
just go tell him what you want to say.
你就直接說出你想說的
It's simple.
很簡單
Make him get angry at your stupidity and come home.
讓他覺得你很笨，惹他生氣再回來
Advice?
建議？
Are you stupid or what?
你是笨蛋嗎？
Yes.
是
You're asking the wrong person.
你問錯人了吧
Sorry, but I'm a very busy man.
抱歉，但我是個大忙人
Forgive us.
請原諒我們
Make him get angry at your stupidity and come home.
讓他覺得你很笨，惹他生氣再回來
That job you're so busy with…
您這麼忙著做的工作
What is it exactly?
到底是什麼？
From my point of view,
在我看來
all you do is give out Impact Factor and get people promotions.
你就只是給別人影響因子 幫助他們獲得升遷
-That's what it looks like to me. -Dr. Sera.
-在我看來就只是這樣 -世良醫生
These papers, they're like students' essays.
這些論文就像是學生的作文一樣
You give them a big thumbs up
你稱讚他們做得好
and throw a big party to pat yourselves on the back.
他們就大肆慶祝，然後對你百般奉承
I don't see the fun in that at all.
我一點都不覺得這很有趣
I'll be leaving now.
我先告辭了
Please… wait.
拜託，等等
Please--
拜託…
What is it you want?
你到底想怎樣？
Showing up like this.
這樣突然出現
A doctor asking for help like this, it's absurd!
自己是醫生卻這樣要我幫忙 太荒謬了吧
I'm not a doctor.
我才不是什麼醫生
Even in the face of a life that needs to be saved,
面對有生命危險的病患
I'm useless.
我一點用都沒有
I'm not a doctor at all.
我根本不能算是醫生
I'll tell you about the doctors I know.
讓我說說我認識的醫生是什麼樣
One never shies away from life-threatening decisions,
有一位在面對生死決定時，從不逃避
leading the way and fighting to save lives every day.
每天都在第一線奮戰，拯救性命
Another believes in technology, hoping to create
另一位相信科技，希望能創造出
a future where more lives will be saved.
能拯救更多生命的未來
And one more.
還有一位
This man is like the devil himself,
他簡直就像惡魔一樣
always saying the craziest things, getting me into trouble too.
總是說一些瘋狂的話 也會讓我惹上麻煩
But he always saves lives, without fail.
但他總是不遺餘力地救人
With his own hands,
用自己的雙手
he saves the lives in front of him.
拯救眼前的每一位病患
I respect them all.
我尊敬他們每一個人
They are all great doctors.
他們都是醫生中的醫生
At Tojo University,
在東城大學裡
they're working away on operation simulations.
我們團隊不停練習模擬手術
But they are not making any progress.
但是沒有任何進展
Searching the globe for medical cases that could give a hint
大家也拚命尋找 全世界的相似病例做參考
on making the operation a success.
一心只想能確保手術的成功
They've all thrown away their pride of using a scalpel
他們全都拋下了醫生親手執刀的尊嚴
in order to save one man's life.
只為了救一個人
That's because Dr. Saeki's life…
因為那是佐伯教授的性命
represents the lives of the thousands of patients awaiting his care.
那代表等著他救的成千上萬人的命
Of course I know…
我當然知道
there's nothing I can do.
我無能為力
But I won't give up.
但我不會放棄
I cannot give up on a life that is right in front of me.
我不能放棄眼前的任何一個性命
That's why I'm here.
所以我才會來這裡
I'm trying to do everything I can.
不管怎樣，我都要試試看
I want to be a doctor too.
我也想成為醫生
So I ask you, please.
所以我拜託您了
Won't you help us?
您願意幫幫我們嗎？
I beg of you.
我求求您！
Please!
拜託！
I indeed recall seeing
我記得看過一篇研究
a case similar to Dr. Saeki's where the Darwin was used.
跟佐伯教授的病例類似 是用達爾文完成的
A report of a similar successful surgery.
手術的結果很成功
Still unknown to the world,
刊登那篇研究的期刊
it's from a small research magazine in America.
世界知名度不高 是美國一家小型研究所出的
I have connections, so I'll ask about it myself.
我有人脈，可以幫你們問問
You will?
真的嗎？
Thank you.
非常謝謝您
No.
不用客氣
After all,
畢竟
that's what these papers are for.
這才是論文的意義所在
When I was young, I was diagnosed with a rare sickness.
我小時候得了一種罕見疾病
They said I wouldn't live long.
他們都說我活不了多久
But despite the odds, my physician at the time
但是，我當時的主治醫生
scoured the globe for papers and found a way to treat me.
找遍了全世界的論文 終於找到治療我的方法
Research by someone, somewhere in the world…
世界上某個地方、某個人的研究
will save people in other countries.
能夠拯救其他國家的人的性命
That's what papers are for.
這就是論文的意義
As you said,
就像你說的
it's not for someone's promotion.
這不是為了誰能夠升遷
It's to save lives.
而是為了救人
Making sure they're read is my job.
我的工作就是 確保論文能被其他人看到
Thank you for reminding me.
謝謝你提醒了我
I pray for your success.
我祝你們成功
Thank you.
謝謝
This is the report I received from Mr. Ikenaga.
這是我從池永主編那裡收到的資料
This is indeed similar to Dr. Saeki's case.
確實與佐伯醫生的情況很類似
We hadn't thought of this approach.
我們沒想過用這樣的方式處理
Finally, the light at the end of the tunnel.
終於出現一線曙光了
All right. We'll use this to form a new plan.
太好了，我們以此制定新計畫吧
-Right. -Understood.
-是
The new plan was different from previous simulations.
新的治療計畫與先前模擬的完全不同
Instead of two operations using separate entrance routes,
不從兩個路徑進入，做兩種手術
they would enter through one hole and do both a bypass and the mitral valve.
而是只透過一個路徑 來完成搭橋術和二尖瓣修補手術
A completely new approach.
這是全新的方法
By operating with only one opening, surgery time would shortened,
只開一個洞能夠減少手術時間
making the impossible possible.
將不可能化為可能
The only way.
這是唯一的方法
Thanks to you, Dr. Tokai, we've finally found a way to operate.
渡海醫生，託你的福 我們終於找到手術方法了
I didn't think you would actually find something.
沒想到真的讓你找到了
I did.
是啊
But we don't have time and we don't know if this method will actually--
但我們時間不多了 這方法真的能用嗎？
Don't think about it, just do it.
不用想這個，做就對了
If you kill the doctor,
如果教授死了
I'll kill you all.
我就把你們全都殺了
I have to keep him alive for now.
現在還得留他一命呢
So you can find out more about that patient?
是為了找出那位患者在哪裡嗎？
-Why were you trying to-- -So I can kill Dr. Saeki myself.
-你為什麼要… -為了親手殺死佐伯
This is our plan.
這是我們的計畫
It is theoretically possible.
理論上是可行的
We'll continue simulations for further analysis.
我們會繼續進行模擬試驗 做進一步驗證
If you succeed, it will be a world-first for the Caesar.
如果成功，這會是凱撒的世界首例啊
That's right. I would consider writing a paper about it.
沒錯，我都考慮寫成論文了
Dr. Takashina,
高階醫生
what happened to the Caesar paper you were working on?
你的凱撒論文進行得如何？
Actually, Dr. Nishizaki
事實上，西崎教授
had someone else write it for him.
叫別人幫他寫了
My paper no longer holds any value.
我的論文現在毫無價值了
It's tucked away inside my computer.
檔案就躺在我的電腦裡
I'm glad to hear that.
那真是太好了
What?
什麼？
-Raise it, 60 degrees. -Deeper…
-抬高60度 -深入一點
Time out.
時間到
-Dr. Saeki? -Professor!
-佐伯醫生？ -教授
-Get the electrocardiogram. -Okay!
-準備心電圖 -是！
Professor!
教授！
A heart attack? Take him to the operating room!
心肌梗塞？先帶他到手術室！
-Hey! -Wait!
-快點！ -是
Understood. I'm on my way.
知道了，我馬上過去
Dr. Tokai. The professor's condition has taken a turn for the worse.
渡海醫生，教授的情況突然惡化了
They're doing an emergency surgery.
他們要進行緊急手術
We will now perform a coronary artery bypass
現在開始使用凱撒 進行冠狀動脈搭橋術
and mitral valve repair surgery with the Caesar.
以及二尖瓣修補手術
No matter what, we must save Dr. Saeki's life.
無論如何都要拯救佐伯醫生
-Right. -Okay.
-是
-All right, insert the arm. -Right.
-好，插入機械手臂
Even with simulations not yet complete,
雖然模擬手術尚未完成
because of the heart attack, operating time was shortened even further.
但教授突然心肌梗塞 手術時間會比之前還要短
We only had one hour to operate.
我們只有一小時能完成
TIME LIMIT 59 MINUTES REMAINING
（剩餘時間：59分鐘）
We've reached the internal mammary artery.
到達內乳動脈
Proceeding with the dissection.
繼續進行剝離
So, they're dissecting
剝離內乳動脈
the internal mammary artery to use for the coronary bypass?
是為了做冠狀動脈搭橋術嗎？
This is the best option for the patient.
對患者來說，這是最好的辦法了
Dissection complete.
剝離完成
That was the first hurdle.
跨過第一個難關
Next is the hard part.
接下來才是真正困難的部分
Let's begin the bypass.
開始進行搭橋
Dr. Tokai, are you sure you can go in there?
渡海醫生，你能進去嗎？
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Confirming position of the left coronary artery.
正在確認左冠狀動脈的位置
Damn…
可惡
I can't see the coronary artery at all.
完全看不到冠狀動脈
We'll have to insert the Caesar.
必須插入凱撒了
Bleeding from the right ventricle.
右心室出血
-Gauze. -Right.
-紗布 -是
-Dr. Sekikawa, wipe the camera lens.
-關川，擦一下鏡頭
There isn't enough time. They won't finish at this rate.
時間不夠，這樣下去無法完成了
Dr. Tokai!
渡海醫生
Dr. Tokai is here!
渡海醫生來了
Is he trying to operate instead?
他想要主刀嗎？
If he's trying to make an incision now, it will take even longer.
要是現在開胸，可能會花更久的時間
-Stop him! -Now, please!
-阻止他 -快跟我來
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
They're not going to let you in there.
他們不會讓你進去
-I know that. -What?
-我知道 -什麼？
We have to stop him. We've been ordered to keep him out.
我們得阻止他 教授下令不讓渡海醫生進去
Where's Dr. Tokai?
渡海醫生在哪裡？
He's not coming.
他不會過來的
So he gave up after all?
所以他還是放棄了？
-Sorry, I'm late. -Where were you?
-抱歉我來晚了 -你去哪裡了？
Sorry.
抱歉
Dr. Takashina, is there anything I can do?
高階醫生，我能做些什麼？
-Get me one pack of transfusion. -Right!
-去準備一袋血 -是
It has been 40 minutes. Saturation is dropping.
已經過40分鐘 血氧濃度開始下降了
Damn…
可惡
If we go over the hour limit,
如果超過一小時
his heart could stop at any time.
心臟隨時可能停止
-We have to save him no matter what! -Right.
-不管怎樣都得救教授 -是
-Let's work together.
-拜託了
I can finally see the left coronary artery.
我終於看到左冠狀動脈了
Hold the heart back with gauze.
用紗布球按住心臟
-Got it. -Here.
-好的 -這裡
We have ventricular tachycardia.
心室性心搏過速
The heart couldn't handle the pressure.
心臟無法再承受壓力了
Doctor, let's remove it.
醫生，先拿出來吧
Right.
好
I've lost sight of it again. Damn it.
我又看不到了，可惡
It has been 45 minutes. We only have 15 minutes left.
已經過45分鐘，只剩15分鐘
TIME LIMIT 14 MINUTES REMAINING
（剩餘時間：14分鐘）
I can't reach it…
我碰不到…
It's right there.
明明就近在眼前
Fifteen minutes is not enough.
15分鐘是不夠的
-What is it? -Dr. Takashina.
-怎麼了？ -高階醫生
If the Caesar goes in any further
凱撒再繼續深入
it will only damage the heart.
只會損傷心臟而已
We can't go any further than this…
無法再往前了
Oh, no…
不會吧…
So the professor…
所以教授…
Dr. Saeki…
佐伯教授…
can't be saved.
回天乏術了
What are you saying?
你在說什麼？
That cannot be.
不可能
I won't accept the professor's life being taken away!
我絕對不接受教授的生命在這裡結束
Dr. Saeki,
佐伯教授
for years and years,
年復一年
has saved hundreds and thousands of lives!
拯救了成千上萬名患者的性命
God!
上帝也好
The devil!
惡魔也好
I don't care who!
不管是誰都行
Please!
拜託
Please save the professor!
救救教授吧！
-Dr. Takashina? -We need 4-0.
-高階醫生 -給我4-0號線
Right.
是
-It moved. -The arm moved.
-移動了 -手臂移動了
What is going on?
這是怎麼一回事？
Excuse me.
不好意思
I'll tell you what.
就是這麼一回事
All right.
好
First, we stop the bleeding in the right ventricle.
首先，右心室要先止血
Remote operation.
遠端手術
Dr. Tokai gave me the orders.
這是渡海醫生吩咐我的
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
They're not going to let you in there.
他們不會讓你進去
-I know that. -What?
-我知道 -什麼？
I'll use the other Caesar in the office.
我會在辦公室裡操作另一台凱撒
Remote operation.
遠端進行手術
Go get permission to use the Caesar in the operating room.
你去取得手術室那台凱撒的連線許可
Go.
快點
REMOTE OPERATION CONNECTING
（遠端操作連線中）
-Sorry, I'm late. -Where were you?
-抱歉我來晚了 -你去哪裡了？
Sorry.
抱歉
Dr. Takashina, is there anything I can do?
高階醫生，我能做些什麼？
REMOTE OPERATION REQUESTED
（遠端操作申請）
-Get me one back of transfusion. -Right!
-去準備一袋血 -是
It has been 40 minutes. Saturation is dropping.
已經過40分鐘 血氧濃度開始下降了
REMOTE OPERATION ACCESS GRANTED
（遠端操作連接許可通過）
I'm sorry I didn't have time to explain.
抱歉，我沒時間解釋
We thought the simulator was of no use.
我們以為那個模擬器沒用了
Using it like this is…
沒想到能像這樣使用
Your plan wasn't bad.
你們的計畫不錯
It was actually quite good.
其實想得很周到
This approach could indeed work.
從這裡進去的話，確實可行
But…
但是…
You aren't able to see the coronary artery.
看不到最關鍵的冠狀動脈
The Caesar cannot be inserted any further in this condition.
在這種情況下，凱撒無法更深入了
If you can't get in deeper, we'll have to pull the heart out.
如果凱撒無法更深入 把心臟拉出來不就好了
Pull it out? How?
拉出來？怎麼做？
-With a suction cup. -A suction cup?
-用吸盤 -吸盤？
We'll use a suction cup and pull the heart out.
用吸盤把心臟吸出來
You can't just…
你不能就這樣…
Right ventricle suture complete. You're up.
好，右心室縫合完成，換你了
-Right ventricle suture complete. -Fifty minutes elapsed. We have no time!
-右心室縫合完成 -已經過了50分鐘，快沒時間了
TIME LIMIT 9 MINUTES REMAINING
（剩餘時間：9分鐘）
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
-What is it, Dr. Takashina? -Dr. Takashina.
-高階，怎麼了？ -高階醫生
-Dr. Takashina, the next steps, hurry! -I know.
-高階醫生，快進行下一步 -我知道
We'll now proceed with the left coronary artery bypass surgery.
接著進行左冠狀動脈搭橋術
-Bring a suction cup. -Suction cup? That wasn't in the plan.
-把吸盤拿過來 -吸盤？那不在計畫裡啊
I've got one ready.
我拿過來了
All right. Here we go.
好，開始吧
-We'll do anything we can! -Right!
-我們要用盡全力！ -是！
Here.
這裡
The heart is coming toward the Caesar.
心臟往凱撒那邊過去了
The heart won't stabilize like that.
但是這樣心臟會不穩
There's no arm to hold it like the Darwin.
凱撒不像達爾文有機械手臂能扶著
-I'll suture with one hand. -With one hand?
-我用單手縫合 -單手？
The left arm will hold the heart and the right will suture.
左手穩住心臟，用右手縫合
Got it.
我知道了
Almost at one hour.
一小時快到了
Come on… let's make it work!
快啊，一定要成功
TIME LIMIT 4 MINUTES REMAINING
（剩餘時間：4分鐘）
He's using his right hand only.
他真的只用右手
Amazing. I've never seen it done.
太厲害了，我從沒見過
Hurry up with the thread. Stay focused!
縫線跟得太慢了，專心點！
Got it.
知道了
-Suction!
-抽吸
Sorry.
抱歉
-Blower next.
-充氣
-Hurry up. -Let's pick up the pace.
-快點 -速度跟上
-Right! -Okay!
-是
-Arai. -Yes?
-新井護理師 -是？
Get the blood flow pumps.
準備輸血管和排血管
What?
什麼？
Okay.
好
-Amazing. -The arm is moving so much faster.
-太厲害了 -手臂動得好快
We might actually make it.
或許真的辦得到
Bypass complete.
搭橋完成
We did it in an hour.
我們在一小時內完成了
We made it.
成功了
But the mitral valve surgery still needs to be done.
但還需要做二尖瓣修補手術
-We've made it this far. -Damn.
-都好不容易到這個地步了 -可惡
Use the heart-lung machine.
使用人工心肺機
What?
什麼？
We'll do it on-pump beating heart style.
我們要做體外循環心臟二尖瓣手術
The Saeki Method with the Caesar?
用凱撒做佐伯式手術？
Is that possible?
這有可能嗎？
Who knows?
誰知道？
But we have to try.
但我們總得試試
Dr. Takashina!
高階！
Understood.
我知道了
We'll now use the Caesar
我們現在要用凱撒
to perform on-pump beating heart mitral valve repair surgery.
進行體外循環心臟二尖瓣修補手術
-What? -The Saeki Method with the Caesar?
-什麼？ -用凱撒做佐伯式手術？
Those were the orders. Turn on the heart-lung machine.
聽從主刀醫生的指示 啟動人工心肺機
-Right. -Blood flow pumps!
-是 -輸血管和排血管
Here they are.
來了
Here.
這裡
-Hurry. -Right.
-快點 -是
All right. Next…
好，接下來
We will begin mitral valve repair.
進行二尖瓣修復手術
-Right. -Okay.
-是 -好的
His skills are godlike.
簡直是神技
It's like watching Dr. Saeki operate.
就像佐伯醫生本人在動手術
Doctor.
醫生
It's all right.
沒事
You're doing great, Dr. Takashina.
做得好，高階
Thank you.
謝謝
Dr. Takashina.
高階
Using my real hands is a hundred times easier.
我親手開刀還更簡單一百倍
Complete.
完成
What's his condition?
情況如何？
Blood pressure…
血壓…
Stabilized.
穩定了
All right!
太好了
-We did it!
-成功了！ -我們辦到了！
It was written here the whole time.
原來一直都寫在這裡
Dr. Tokai is really an incredible person.
渡海醫生真的很厲害
He is.
是啊
Professor.
教授
So I'm still alive.
所以我還活著啊
-We're glad you're here. -If I'm still alive,
-很高興您還活著 -如果是這樣
then there's more work
那我還有更多的工作…
to be done.
要完成
NEW MESSAGE
（您有新訊息，開啟）
After that, the new issue of the Japan Surgical Journal was published.
手術之後 新一期的《日本外科期刊》發行了
Congratulations, Dr. Nishizaki.
西崎教授，恭喜
Thank you. You've done well too.
謝謝，你也做得很好
What the hell is this?
這是什麼鬼？
Saeki…
佐伯
It's a Caesar paper written independently by Tojo University.
這是東城大學獨立完成的凱撒論文
Apart from the paper itself,
論文很傑出就不用說了
the video attached was great.
附上的影片更精彩
The Saeki Method executed through remote operation of the Caesar.
遠端操作凱撒機器人進行佐伯式手術
MEDICAL ROBOT CAESAR PAPER
（凱撒論文）
A top-notch surgery made possible by a top-notch surgeon
一流的外科醫生使用一流的醫療器具
using top-notch technology.
才能完成如此一流的手術
I won't stand for this!
這口氣我吞不下去！
It's against the rules of collaborative research!
這違反了合作研究的規則
I've decided that the paper from Tojo will better benefit future patients.
我認為東城大學的論文 未來能夠幫助更多的患者
Thank you for your time.
那我就說到這
What… Hello?
什麼？喂？
Takashina…
高階
JAPAN SURGICAL JOURNAL
（日本外科期刊）
This is pretty good work.
你真的寫得很好
You put your life on the line for this paper.
畢竟是攸關教授您性命的論文
It's all thanks to your cooperation.
一切都多虧了你的協助
Was Dr. Tokai's use of the Caesar
渡海醫生會使用凱撒的事
part of your plan as well?
您早就料到了嗎？
Dr. Tokai won't let me die just yet.
渡海現在還不會讓我死
Forgive me,
不好意思
but if you'll excuse us…
能請你迴避一下嗎？
Thanks to you, I live to see another day.
多虧有你，我才活了下來
I take it you've come here to kill me now.
所以你現在是要來殺了我的吧？
Where is Tatsuji Iinuma?
飯沼達次在哪裡？
I cannot tell you that.
我不能告訴你
There's something…
我還有事情…
I still have to do.
必須要完成
You must be careful not to leak information about the patient.
你絕對不能洩漏患者資訊
Okay.
是
All right.
好的
Please take care of him.
接下來就請你照顧他了
This sure brings me back.
真是懷念啊
You know, a long time ago…
你知道嗎？很久以前
I was once admitted here at Tojo.
我也曾在東城大學住院過
Is that so?
是嗎？
I told you, didn't I?
我告訴過你吧？
There's only one man in this world
世界上只有一個人
who can use the black forceps.
可以使用黑色止血鉗
I'm not ready to hand them over to you just yet.
所以我現在還不能交給你
Then I'll just have to take them myself.
那我只好用搶的了
By the way…
順便…
My father lost everything to these forceps,
我爸因為這把止血鉗失去了一切
and now, it's your turn!
現在換你了
So we finally meet.
我們終於見面了
-The patient comes first. -You're a patient too!
-病患優先 -你也是病患！
The forceps…
止血鉗
It's almost time. This is where it will all end.
時間快到了，這就是一切終結的地方
Stop, Dr. Tokai!
住手，渡海醫生！
You've opened up the gates of hell.
你打開了地獄之門
Subtitle translation by: Tom Grathwol
字幕翻譯：林婉婷